prothemedesign.com 2018-09-07

# Privacy Policy

At Pro Theme Design we take privacy very seriously. We also recognise the importance of protecting and respecting your personal data. This privacy policy is here to tell you what personal data is collected on this site, how the data is used, and how you can contact us regarding your personal data.

## What data is being collected?

When using our site there are different types of Personal Data that might be collected. The data might be collected by the site itself or through third parties.

Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Website is required by the Website to provide its services.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party’s consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## How the data is collected?

On Pro Theme Design personal data may be collected in a number of ways.

### Contact Forms

The main method for us collecting data is through our contact forms. Here you will supply your name and email address so that we can respond to your messages. Our contact forms use a third party service called Formspree. The [Formspree privacy policy](http://docs.formspree.io/files/privacy.pdf) can be read here: http://docs.formspree.io/files/privacy.pdf

### Online Purchases

When purchasing a product you will be asked for additional information, such as address and credit card information. These are not seen directly by us at Pro Theme Design and are stored securely with our payment provider Fastspring. The [Fastspring privacy policy](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) can be read here: https://fastspring.com/privacy/.

Once a purchase is verified we are given a payment notification which tells us your email address and the product you purchased. We use this to generate and verify license keys for your purchase(s).

### Newsletter

We use Mailchimp as our newsletter service. In order to sign up for the newsletter you are required to give them your email address. All emails contain an unsusbcribe link which you can use at any time. The [Mailchimp Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) can be seen here: https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/.

## Who might we share your data with?

  * **Google Analytics** – We share your IP address, and browsing behaviour, with analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site. (https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)
  * **YouTube** – is a video hosting service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Website to add videos to our site. (https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines)
  * **GfyCat** \- is an animated gif hosting site that allows us to add optimised animated gifs to our site. (https://gfycat.com/privacy)
  * **Google Fonts** \- is a font hosting service that allows us to easily serve unique fonts to our visitors. (https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq)
  * **Cloudflare** \- is a website optimization service that helps us to make our website fast and secure for our visitors. (https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/)
  * **Social networks and other websites** – Our website includes links to other websites, whose privacy practices may be different from ours. If you submit Personal Information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

We do not otherwise share or supply personal information to third parties. We do not sell or rent your personal information to marketers or third parties.

## What do we do with your data?

The data we collect from you is used to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient and customised experience. By submitting your information on this website, you agree that we may use your information for the following purposes:

  * Fulfilling Your Requests – we use your e-mail addresses to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us.
  * Customer Service – We communicate with our users on a regular basis via email to provide requested services and help you manage your account. As we are obligated to send these communications to current customers, if you do not wish to receive these communications at all, then, unfortunately, you must close your account.
  * Email Marketing – we also use your email address to send you other types of communications that you can control, including information about new themes, customer surveys and special promotions.

## How long do we keep hold of your information?

We retain purchase information for the purposes of reporting, backup, and license verification indefinitely so that we can continue to verify purchase data. Where you have requested that we do so, we will take steps to delete your data from our system.

## How can I access information you hold about me?

The GDPR gives European visitors certain rights over their data. We are happy to extend these same rights to everyone, worldwide.

These rights give you the ability to verify and seek rectification of your data, delete data, export data and more. Please contact us if you would like to excercise these rights.

## Contact

If you wish to contact us about anything in this policy then please contact us through our contact form, or at _support at prothemedesign dot com_.
